(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
あの続く場所にいますか
Are you in that place that continues on?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Will you stay smiling, as you always do?
今はただそれを願い続ける
For now, I'll just keep on wishing for that
もう一度、もう一度と、もう何度思ったでしょう
"Once more, once more"—I wonder how many times I've thought that.
枯れた花束、捨てられもせず
The withered bouquet, still unable to be thrown away.
降り止まぬ雨は、まるで万雷の拍手喝采
The unceasing rain is like a thunderous round of applause.
愚かな後悔を、嘲笑う怒涛のよう
Like a surging tide laughing at my foolish regrets.
壊れても、なお美しく、胸を刻むのは
Even if broken, what still carves into my heart beautifully...
砕けても、なお美しく、ひとひらの記憶
Even if shattered, what's still beautiful is a single petal of memory.
忘れたいのに、なお狂おしく、胸に残るのは
Even though I want to forget, what remains in my heart, still so maddening...
痛みさえ忘れさせた、微かな感触
A faint sensation that made me forget even the pain.
痛みさえ忘れさせた...
I let it be forgotten...
微かな感触
a faint sensation.
「なんでいなくなっちゃうの…」
"Why are you leaving me...?"
「こんなの苦しいよ…」
"This hurts so much..."
「そばにいて…」
"Stay with me..."
「いつも、そばにいるよ。」
"I'm always by your side."
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you’ve already forgotten
夏の木陰に座ったまま、氷菓を口に放り込んで風を待っていた
The way we sat in the summer shade, sucking on popsicles and waiting for the breeze
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you’ve already forgotten
世の中の全部嘘だらけ、本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
How the world was filled with lies, and we laughed and promised to go find the true value of things together
忘れないように
So that I won't forget
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that things left in physical form aren't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming
僕が描いてる目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
What was reflected in the eyes I was drawing was the ghost of summer
風にスカートが揺れて
A skirt sways in the wind
思い出なんて忘れて
Forget all about the memories
浅い呼吸をする
Taking a shallow breath
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away the sweat, summer is in the air
もう忘れてしまったかな、夏の木陰に座った頃
I wonder if you’ve already forgotten, the time we sat in the summer shade
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
There was a cloud peeking out from the distant hill, wasn't there?
君はそれを掴もうとして、馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
You tried to catch it, with your hand foolishly cutting through the air
僕は紙に雲一つを描いて、笑って握って見せて
I drew a single cloud on paper, and showed it to you with a smile
忘れないように
So that I won't forget
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because things left in history aren't everything
今だけ顔もなくして
For now, just lose your face
言葉も全部忘れて
Forget all the words
君は笑ってる
And you are laughing
僕を忘れた
You've forgotten me
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me about the scent of summer
浅い呼吸をする
I take a shallow breath
忘れないように
So that I don't forget
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because what resonates in the heart isn't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
さよならだって教えて
Teach me how to say goodbye too
今も見るんだよ
I still see it even now
夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
The ghost in the flower that blooms in summer
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not with words, but with time
時間じゃなくて心を
Not with time, but with the heart
浅い呼吸をする
I take a shallow breath
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away the sweat, it feels like summer
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten
夏の日陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the shade of a summer day
氷菓を口に放り込んで
Popping an ice confection into my mouth
風を待っていた
Waiting for the wind to blow
ということで、赤井はあと爆誕祭2025、始まっちゃいます！
And so, Akai Haato Birthday Festival 2025 is starting!
始まっちゃいます！
It's starting!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、事故、事故、あ...
Ah, wait, a glitch, a glitch, ah...
ああー！危ない危ない！
Aaaah! Watch out, watch out!
1曲目1曲目、まだ体力温存しないと。
That was just the first song, we need to save our energy.
はい、ゲストに来てくれたのは...
Okay, the guest joining us today is...
らでんちゃん！
Raden-chan!
こんばんは！ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございまーす！
Good evening! I'm Juufuutei Raden from hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS!
ありがとう、来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
はあちゃま、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Haachama, happy birthday to you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そして新衣装じゃないですか！
And look at that new outfit!
そうなんです！サラララララ...
That's right! Look at it spin...
綺麗！可愛い！
Beautiful! So cute!
いや、この衣装めっちゃシナジーある。
Wow, this outfit has amazing synergy with mine.
らでんちゃん言ってたけど、これクリスマスカラーだね、二人。
Raden-chan said it, but we're both in Christmas colors.
そうなの！
We are!
らでんはクリスマスツリー。
Raden is the Christmas tree.
そう、はあちゃまはサンタ。
And Haachama is Santa.
サンタです！
I'm Santa!
で、この季節にぴったり。
And it's perfect for this season.
ぴったりですね。夏の匂いがします。
Perfect indeed. Though it smells like summer.
夏の匂いがします。スイカ系だね、はあちゃま。
It does. You look like a watermelon, Haachama.
クリスマスだと思ってんだよ！
I thought it was Christmas!
タグもね、#赤井はあと爆誕祭2025 でね
Use the hashtag #AkaiHaatoBirthdayFestival2025
ぜひともSNSでスクショとかツイートしてください！
and please post screenshots and tweets on SNS!
お願いします！
Please do!
じゃあ、なんか写真撮ろうか！
Now, let's take some photos!
ぜひ撮りましょう！おしとやかなポーズ行きますか！
Let's! Shall we go with a graceful pose?
せっかくなんで。
Since we're together.
ガッツリね！
Strike it firmly!
決めポーズ！おしとやかなポーズ。
Signature pose! A graceful pose.
二人は、ホロライブ！
The two of us are Hololive!
はっ！
Ha!
強そう！強そう！最強！
Looks strong! Strong! The strongest!
最強！鉄壁！
Strongest! Ironclad defense!
えー、じゃあ、どうしようかな。
Hmm, what should we do next...
あ、ちょっと、はあとで。今時な、はあとで。
Ah, let's do a heart. A trendy heart.
はあとで！いいじゃないっすか！
A heart! That's great!
あ、可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
そして、そして、はあと！
And another heart!
うわぁぁぁ！
Waaaaah!
いーやー、らでんちゃん大丈夫か！
Nooo, Raden-chan, are you okay!
戻ってきて、戻ってきて！
Come back, come back!
うち等の仲じゃないっすか！
Aren't we on good terms!?
ホロライブ！
Hololive!
危ない危ない。あ、今のはね、喝を入れただけだから！
Watch out. Ah, that was just a pep talk!
喝入れられました、まずいまずい。
I got quite the pep talk, this is bad.
殴ったりとかしないからね、別に、あはは。
I won't hit you or anything, really, haha.
しっとりした曲歌った後ですから。
It's because we just sang a mellow song.
しゃなりとね。しゃなりとね。
Gracefully, right. Gracefully.
みんなスクショ撮ってくれてるか！
Is everyone taking screenshots!
写真撮って保存するんだぞ！
Take photos and save them!
お願いします！
Please!
まあそんなわけで、今回ですね、我々は...
Anyway, this time, we are...
そうですよ、我々ユニット名「放浪ライブ」ですから！
That's right, our unit name is 'Horolive' (Wandering-live)!
いつからできたの？
Since when was that formed?
なんかだいぶ前に。
Quite a while ago.
放浪ライブという感じでね、らでんちゃんを呼ばせていただきました！
I invited Raden-chan to join 'Horolive'!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そしてね、あの衣装もシナジーがあるってわけで…
And you see, our outfits also have synergy...
えー「花に亡霊」を歌ったんですけども、どうでした？
We sang "Ghost in a Flower," how was it?
エモ！
Emotional!
いやエモ。このステージとすっごい合ってたし…
No, emotional. It matched this stage perfectly, and...
やっぱね、あのらでんちゃんに歌ってほしいパートがあったんですよ。
There was a part I really wanted Raden-chan to sing.
え？どこどこ？
Eh? Where, where?
「歴史に残るものだけがすべてじゃない」っていうところで…
The part "What remains in history isn't everything"...
あ、これちょっとらでんちゃんに歌ってほしいなと思って…
Ah, I thought I'd like Raden-chan to sing this...
レパートリーをあげさせてもらいました。
so I added it to the repertoire.
嬉しい！
I'm happy!
私もどこかで歌いたいなーって思ってたから…
Because I'd been thinking I wanted to sing it too...
そう、この曲一緒に歌いたいんだって言ってくれた時、めちゃ嬉しい！と思って。
Right, when you said you wanted to sing this together, I was so happy!
よかったー。嬉しい。ありがとうございます。
I'm so glad. I'm happy. Thank you very much.
じゃあ。頑張って帰ってね。
Well then. Good luck getting back.
こ、ここから？ここから？え？
He- Here? From here? Eh?
うわ！じゃ、じゃあ、ほな！ほな！
Whoa! Well, then, see ya! See ya!
これからも頑張ってください！
Please keep doing your best!
ありがとう！頑張ってください。
Thank you! Please do your best.
これどうやって帰るの？これどうやって帰るの？
How do I get back? How do I get back?
あ、あっち？あっち？…あ、あっち？
Ah, that way? That way? ...Ah, that way?
らでんちゃんありがとう！頑張ってください！バイバイ！
Raden-chan, thank you! Do your best! Bye-bye!
愛して愛して愛して
Love Me, Love Me, Love Me
作詞・作曲・きくお
Lyrics & Composition: Kikuo
遥か遠い遠い昔　巻かれた首輪
A collar wrapped around me in the distant, distant past
人が欲しい　人が欲しいと叫ぶ呪いの首輪
A cursed collar that cries, "I want people, I want people"
怒らないで　見捨てないで　どこも行かないで
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere
強く締める　悪魔に締める　人がいない　いないと
Tighten it strongly, tighten it by the devil, there are no people
良い成績でしょ？
Good results, right?
ねえ　ねえ　良い子でしょ？
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
かわいい子でしょ？
A cute child, right?
ねえ　ねえ　良い子でしょ？
Hey, hey, I'm a good child, right?
苦しいね
It's painful, isn't it
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me
もっと　もっと
More and more
愛して　愛して
Love me, love me
苦しいほどに
Until it's painful
苦しい　苦しい
Painful, painful
呪縛を
The curse
解いて　解いて
Undo it, undo it
ねえ
Hey
止められない　嗚呼
I can't stop it, aa
体　体　大きくなっても小さい首輪
Body, body, even as it grows, the collar is small
足りなくなる　足りなくなる　人が人が足りない
It's not enough, not enough, people are not enough
クラスの誰にも負けない綺麗ないい子でしょ
I'm a beautiful, good child who won't lose to anyone, right?
どこより　どの子より　誰も彼も私を見てよ
More than anyone, more than any child, everyone look at me
体育館裏　あなたに告白を
Behind the gym, a confession to you
嘘みたいでしょ？　あなたが好きなの
It's like a lie, right? I love you
汚いあなたが
You, who are filthy
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me
全部あげる　あなたに　あなたに
I'll give it all to you, to you
全部背負ってもらうよ
I'll have you shoulder it all
足りない　あなたが　足りない
It's not enough, you are not enough
離さないよ　嗚呼
I won't let you go, aa
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry
愛して　愛して　愛して
Love me, love me, love me
もっと　もっと
More and more
愛して　愛して
Love me, love me
狂おしいほどに
Madly enough to be painful
苦しい
It's painful
離さない
I won't let go
苦しい
It's painful
もっと　もっと
More and more
ねえ
Hey
幸せなの　嗚呼
I'm happy, aa
幸せなの
I'm so happy.
Yeah!
Ina, Risu, and Haachama!
We are finally here together at the birthday!
Yeah, and look at this!
This is a pair!
I need one too.
A chainsaw too!
Oh wow, that's heavy.
Okay, let's go! Yeah!
I feel so 'Doryoku, Mirai, A Beautiful Star'!
I feel so 'Effort, Future, A Beautiful Star'!
Yeah! Ina and Risu!
And Haato-chan... What a nice chainsaw!
'Aishite Aishite Aishite' was so nice!
'Love me, love me, love me' was so nice!
Yeah, I'm so happy to be singing together!
Yeah! And also, Happy Birthday, Haachama!
Yeah, it's a really nice birthday today!
Thank you for letting us celebrate it with you!
And thanks for inviting us!
So fun! Yeah!
It's the first time that we are together as a group.
Yeah! Ina, Risu, and Haato-chan... We are...
Hachirisa!
We just jumbled our names together! Hachirisa!
Yeah! Let's take a picture!
Okay! Everyone take a picture! Patcha!
Okay! Everyone take a picture! Click!
ガオー！
Rawr!
Nice!
Yeah! Nice screenshot! That's so cool!
No no no, dangerous, dangerous!
Let's fight! Let's kill them!
On camera? Yeah, on camera!
Say goodbye! Bye bye!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり
That you're all alone...
XXし
Doing "XX"...
てるの知ってるよ
...I know you're doing it.
知ってるよ
I know, I know.
びくんびくん震えてさ
Twitching and trembling,
声もだだ漏れなんだわ
your voice is leaking out completely.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just be honest and say it,
バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
you've been found out anyway, so say it.
聴いてんの？
Are you listening?
ふふふ 恥ずかしい
Hehehe, how embarrassing.
皆隠しているだけ
Everyone is just hiding it.
モニタリング
Monitoring
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり涙してるの知ってるよ
I know you're crying all alone.
ぐすんぐすんへこんでさ
Sniffling and feeling down,
弱音吐いたっていいんじゃない？
isn't it okay to show some weakness?
朝が来るまで一生懸命
Until morning comes, with all your might,
もっと泣いたっていいんだよ
it's okay to cry even more.
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept you as many times as it takes.
もう我慢しないで いっぱい出してね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
おねがい 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Please, I want you. Let me comfort you.
SHAKE SHAKE 愛のサインで
SHAKE SHAKE, with a sign of love,
泣いてくれなきゃ
if you don't cry for me...
ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ
No, no, no, no, no.
ねえいいでしょ その全部を飲み干したい
Hey, it's okay, right? I want to drink it all up.
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Da-da-da-darling!
おねがい 君が欲しいの 手をぶら下げて
Please, I want you. Hanging your hands down,
SHAKE SHAKE なんて最高ね
SHAKE SHAKE, how wonderful.
化けてくれなきゃ
If you don't change for me...
ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ ヤだ
No, no, no, no, no.
ねえいいでしょ その胃袋を救いたい
Hey, it's okay, right? I want to save that stomach of yours.
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Da-da-da-darling!
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり気合してんの知ってるよ
I know you're firing yourself up alone.
ずくんずくんたまるじゃん
It's building up, throbbing,
君を推すことはやめない
I won't stop supporting you.
ねぇあたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君はできる子知ってるよ
I know you're a capable person.
辛い時は弱いぐらいでちょうどいい
When things are tough, being a bit weak is just right.
あたしそれでも好きだよ
I still love you regardless.
おねがい 君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
Please, I want you. Call my name.
いつだって 愛の感情
Always, the feelings of love,
君は独りじゃない
you are not alone.
だから歌って 独り占め
So sing, and keep it all to yourself.
ねえいいでしょ そのプレイはおしまいな
Hey, it's okay, right? That play is over.
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Da-da-da-darling!
君が病める時も
Even when you are sick,
あたしそばにいるわ
I will be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I'm always watching over you.
さぁ早く 怖くないのよ
Come now, quickly. It's not scary.
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I need you
慰めさせてシェイク
Let me soothe you, shake
愛の才能で
With the talent of love
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me
壊れてしまう
I'll end up broken
壊れてたい 泣いているの
I want to be broken, are you crying?
なめて
Lick me
とっっっっても見本です
This is a perfect example
お願い君が欲しいの
Please, I need you
手を打ち鳴らして
Clap your hands together
知らなんて最期
Not knowing the end
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me
君の痛い
Your pain...
感じていたい
...I want to feel it
覗いていたい
I want to keep peeking
吸い取って救いたい
I want to suck it up and save you
ねえ 私知っているよ
Hey, I know
君のこと全部知っているの
I know everything about you
吸い込んで
Suck it in
最後までいいんじゃない
Isn't it fine until the very end?
朝が来るまで
Until morning comes
一緒に遊ぼう
Let's play together
止まったって
Even if we stop
何度だって 止めてあげる
I'll stop you as many times as it takes
もがもがしないで
Don't struggle
オトノケ
Otonoke
諦めも悪りゃあ
If you're a bad loser...
あんたの中じゃ
...then within you
どこまでも彼方 クワバラ クワバラ
You're far away, knock on wood
目にも止まらぬ速さで
At a speed the eye can't even catch
ダバラン タバラン さながら
Just like daban-taban
おひとついかがなもんか 棘だらけの邪魔
How about one? A thorn-filled nuisance
俺はもう一人のあなた
I am your other self
サラチャン コヨチャン ワサカ
Sara-chan, Koyo-chan, maybe...
黄泉の国 ワダラ
The land of the dead, wadara...
肺入れた 肺入れた 肺入れた...
I'm in, I'm in, I'm in...
軋して這い入れた 裂けで霧は晴れた
Squeezed in, crawled in, the mist cleared by tearing
凸と凹がうまく噛み合ったら
When the convex and concave mesh perfectly
痛みが薬になったら
When pain becomes medicine
心 体 頭 みなぎってゆく
Heart, body, head, overflowing
鮮やか背中に今花が咲いたならば
If a vivid flower blooms on my back now
暗闇からさらば
Farewell to the darkness
飛び立ってゆく体
A body taking flight
心 体 頭 懐かしい暖かさ
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth
足元に今花が咲いたならば
If a flower blooms at my feet now
暗闇からさらば
Farewell to the darkness
飛び立ってゆく体
A body taking flight
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I'll live again and again, inside you and him
瞼の暗闇の中
Inside the darkness of eyelids
胸の奥に居座り続けるメロディ
A melody that remains deep in the chest
リズムに
To the rhythm
今日も冴え渡る眼力
A sharp gaze again today
積み上げてくTop Top
Piling up, top top
鬼とチャンバラ リリカル・ジャスト・マサカー
Swordplay with demons, a lyrical just massacre
漂う大海原 鼻歌口ずさみシャララ
Floating on the vast ocean, humming sha-la-la
祓いたいんなら 待て待てのスッタパ
If you want to exorcise, wait, wait, cut it out
誰が開いたかパンドラ 跡は何があっても知らんがな
Who opened Pandora? I don't care what follows
何百年待ったか 超久しぶりのシャバだ
How many centuries have I waited? It's been a while
ガキや若造 丸こじじゃねえよ 馬鹿が
Brats and youngsters, it's not a complete lie, idiots
今確かに目が合ったな こういうことかよシャマら
Our eyes just met, so that's how it is, folks
肺入れた 肺入れた 肺入れた...
I'm in, I'm in, I'm in...
眠り飽きた先で君が待ってた
You were waiting at the end of being tired of sleeping
盾と矛が肩を抱き合ったら
When the shield and spear embraced each other
怒りが消え去ったら
When anger has vanished
心 体 頭 みなぎってゆく
Heart, body, head, overflowing
鮮やか背中に今花が咲いたならば
If a vivid flower blooms on my back now
暗闇からさらば
Farewell to the darkness
飛び立ってゆく体
A body taking flight
心 体 頭 懐かしい暖かさ
Heart, body, head, a nostalgic warmth
足元に今花が咲いたならば
If a flower blooms at my feet now
暗闇からさらば
Farewell to the darkness
飛び立ってゆく体
A body taking flight
何度だって生きる お前や君の中
I'll live again and again, inside you and him
瞼の暗闇の中
Inside the darkness of eyelids
胸の奥に居座り続けるメロディ
A melody that remains deep in the chest
リズムに
To the rhythm
フー フー フー...
Hoo... hoo... hoo...
ラララ...
La la la...
ちゃま...
Chama...
大切な...
My precious...
家族...
...family.
爆誕ライブの途中ですが
We're in the middle of the birthday live, but
ここからはちょっと外にくり出して
from here, we're going to head outside a bit
ロケをしていこうと思います
and do a location shoot.
ここはですね...
Now, this place is...
私が前から会いたかった方の
I'm at the home of someone
ご自宅ということなんですが
I've wanted to meet for a long time...
とんでもない雰囲気
The atmosphere is incredible.
この階段の先に...
At the top of these stairs...
オカルト界隈でも有名な
a collector famous in the occult world
呪物コレクターの方がいるはずなので
should be there, so...
突撃してみたいと思います
I'm going to go and check it out!
行きましょう
Let's go.
ドキドキ
*Heart pounding*
結構... 階段の段差が...
The stairs... are quite steep...
うおぉぉ
Whoa...
めっちゃ暗い
It's so dark.
一番奥のお部屋のはずなので
It should be the room at the very end,
先に進んで行きましょう
so let's keep going.
なんかスゴイ...
It's amazing...
異質ですね
It feels so strange.
この部屋なんですね
So it's this room.
この一番奥の部屋のはずなので
It should be this room at the very end...
ちょっと...
Well...
表札もないですが
there's no nameplate,
一応ノックしてみますか？
but should I try knocking?
トントン
*Knock knock*
あれ...
Wait...
ここであってますかね？
is this the right place?
もう一度ノックしてみますか
Let's try knocking again.
はい
Yes.
声が...
A voice...
あ...
Ah...
どうも
Hello.
あ、どうも
Oh, hello.
田中さんですか？
Are you Mr. Tanaka?
はい
Yes.
ホロライブ1期生の赤井はあとと申します
I'm Akai Haato from Hololive 1st Gen.
インタビュー撮影に来たんですが
I'm here for an interview...
もし良かったら撮影...
If it's alright, is it okay
大丈夫ですか？
to film here?
大丈夫ですよ
That's fine.
ホントですか？
Really?
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much.
そういえば
By the way,
約束してましたっけ？
did we have an appointment?
すいません
I'm sorry.
忘れてました？
Did you forget?
忘れてましたね
I kind of forgot, yeah.
あ...
Ah...
すでになんか...
I can already see...
色々見えてますけども
all sorts of things here.
入ってもいいですか？
May I come in?
はい、どうぞ
Yes, please.
はい、お願いします
Okay, thank you.
お邪魔します
Pardon me.
失礼します
Excuse me.
これ全部
Are all of these
呪物 なんですか？
cursed objects?
そうなんですよね...
That's right...
呪物というか
Or rather than just objects...
まぁ...
Well...
呪われた...
cursed...
呪われた...モノ
cursed... items.
田中さんは大丈夫なんですか？
Are you okay, Mr. Tanaka?
いやでもずっとしんどいですよ
No, I've felt sick for a long time.
えぇ！？
What!?
全部ちゃんと呪われてる...
So they're all properly cursed...
良いものもありますけど
There are some good ones, though.
呪いにも種類があるんですか？
Are there different types of curses?
ありますね
Yes, there are.
ちなみに今配信を見ている人たちのために
By the way, for the viewers,
田中さんがどんな方なのか
could you introduce yourself
自己紹介してもらっても
and tell us
よろしいですか？
who you are?
呪物コレクター 田中俊行
Curse Collector: Toshiyuki Tanaka
仕事は怪談師なんですよ
My job is a ghost storyteller.
趣味・ライフワークで
As a hobby and lifework,
呪われたものを集めてる
I collect cursed objects.
ちなみに今田中さんが立っている
By the way, are there cursed objects
奥の部屋にも
in that room
呪物があるんですか？
behind you as well?
元々こっちだけが
Originally, only this room
呪物部屋だったんですけど
was the curse room...
量が入りきらなくなって
But I ran out of space.
奥入れますか？
Can we go in?
奥入れますけど...
You can, but...
奥は比較的
In the back, there are many objects
僕が「個人的に契約してる呪物」が多い
that I've personally contracted with.
入らない方がいい
It's better not to go in.
入ったら危ない
It's dangerous if you enter.
あんまし たぶん 呪物が嫌がると思います
I think the curses wouldn't like it.
そんな感じなんだ
Oh, so that's how it is.
最初に入って一番気になったのが
What caught my eye most initially
赤いお面の横にある
was that white mask
白いお面
next to the red one.
あれはどういう呪物なんですか？
What kind of cursed object is that?
“呪いの面”
"The Mask of Curses."
つけると不幸になると言われている
It's said misfortune follows if worn.
実際に不幸が起こっちゃった人がいる？
Has it actually caused misfortune?
京都の蓮久寺っていうお寺
At a temple in Kyoto called Renkyuji,
そこに三木大雲さんという和尚がいる
there's a monk named Daiun Miki.
三木大雲さんから預かったもの
He entrusted this mask to me.
たぶんこれ ピー だと思いますけど
This will probably be beeped, but...
自主規制 と 自主規制 がつけた
[Censored] and [Censored] wore it.
つけたの...！？
They wore it!?
なんでつけちゃったんですか？
Why would they do that?
そういう番組があった
There was a TV show,
試しにつけちゃえみたいな
and they did it just for a lark.
がっつり呪われちゃいましたね
They got seriously cursed.
ちゃんと呪われてる...
So they really were cursed...
基本 お祓いが済んでないもの
Basically, unpurified objects
ここでは普通
are perfectly normal here.
呪物受け取る時に
When I receive objects
人を呪ったものとかありますけど
that were used to curse people,
「お祓いはやめてくれ」って言います
I say, "Don't purify it."
珍しいw
That's unusual lol
意味がなくなるので
Because it loses its meaning.
田中さんおすすめの呪物ありますか？
Do you have any recommendations?
あります あります
I do, I do.
じゃあちょっと持ってきますわ
Alright, I'll go get one.
お願いしま〜す！
Please do!
お人形さんだ！
Oh, a doll!
お人形さん持ってきてくれた
He brought a doll.
奥の部屋あれですよね？
The room in the back,
契約の部屋ですけど
the contract room...
大丈夫なんですか...？
is it okay to go in...?
危険な...
Isn't it dangerous?
出せっていうから...
It told me to bring it out...
可愛いなんか
It's kind of cute...
ジェラピケ着てる
It's wearing Gelato Pique.
やっぱジェラピケなんだ
It really is Gelato Pique!
なんでお気に入りなんですか？
Why is it your favorite?
呪物を集める
Well, when I collect curses...
呪物を集めるきっかけになった人形…
The doll that started your collection...
どういうきっかけで？
How did it start?
元々怪談ライブとかやってたら お客さんが持って来るんですよね
I used to do ghost story lives, and customers would bring them.
えぇぇ…w
Wh-whaaat...?
お祓いとかも出来ると思われてて
They thought I could perform exorcisms too.
ちなみに（お人形の）お名前はなんて？
By the way, what is her name?
チャーミー。 / あ、チャーミーさん。
Charmy. / Oh, Charmy-san.
関西のある介護施設にいたんですよ
She was at a nursing home in Kansai.
へぇ〜そうなんですね
Oh, I see.
で 誰が持ってきたか スタッフの人もわからない
And even the staff didn't know who brought her.
特定の利用者の人が可愛がるんですよね
A certain resident would dote on her.
何故か。 / え、あっ、へぇー。
For some reason. / Oh, wow.
可愛がると
When they dote on her...
三日以内に○ぬんですよ
They die within three days.
えッ…
What...?
それが5人続いたので
That happened to five people in a row.
5人も続いたんですね…
Five people in a row... that's creepy.
なので一度地下の倉庫に隠したんですよ
So, they once hid her in the basement warehouse.
隠されちゃったんだ
She was hidden away.
でも 次の日には出てきてた
But she was back out the next day.
ちゃんと脱出してる…w
She managed to escape... lol
スタッフの人が僕のこと知ってて 田中さんに預けようということで
The staff knew me and decided to entrust her to me.
持ってきてくれたんです
So they brought her to me.
あ なるほど / で バタバタしてたんで 僕はそのまま中身見ずに家に帰った
I see / I was busy so I went home without looking inside.
家に帰ったら…
When I got home...
部屋の明かりが激しく明滅する
The lights in my room started flashing violently.
ｗｗｗｗ
(Laughing)
PC立ち上げてメールの返信しようと思っても
Even when I tried to reply to emails on my PC...
音声認識ソフトが立ち上がって
the voice recognition software kept opening,
他のアプリが開けない
and I couldn't open any other apps.
で なんか気になって その袋を開けたら
I got curious and opened the bag...
この子が出てきた
and this child came out.
その瞬間に現象が一気に止んだ
At that moment, the phenomena stopped instantly.
じゃあもう 早く出してくれっていうやつだったんですかね
So she was like, "Let me out quickly!"
なんかメッセージをたぶん もしかしたら
Maybe it was a message.
でも めっちゃ可愛い服まで着せて 可愛がってますけど… 生きてますね
But you've dressed her so cutely... she's alive.
田中さんは…w
Tanaka-san is... lol
この場では仲良いフリしてますけど
I'm just pretending to be friendly here.
全然可愛がってない？
You're not doting on her at all?
可愛がってないというか 敬ってますけど
It's not doting, I respect her.
霊的な物とか魂みたいな物が宿るんじゃないかと思って
I thought spirits or souls might dwell in objects.
現象が起きた時は怖くなかった？
Weren't you scared when it happened?
いやめちゃくちゃ怖いです / ちゃんと怖かったんだ！
No, it's terrifying / So you were actually scared!
めちゃくちゃ怖いです / 怖くないタイプなのかと思ってました
It's terrifying / I thought you weren't the type to be scared.
次ちょっと…
Next up...
最近送られてきたものがあって それ見てほしいんですけど
There's something sent recently I'd like you to see.
これなんですよ
It's this.
大量の●●●●人形
A huge number of **** dolls.
執着が
The obsession...
「こんなにする？」ってくらい
Like, "how could someone do this?"
すごい遊び方してますね…
That's a wild way to play...
これは遊びじゃなくて… / 遊びじゃないんだ
This isn't play / It's not play...?
姉妹
Sisters.
姉妹の妹が姉を呪ってた
The younger sister was cursing the older one.
ええええ〜
Eeeehhh!?
お姉ちゃんの事を思って
She'd been thinking about her sister...
「○ね○ね○ね」 / そこまでして…！？
"Die, die, die" / Going that far...!?
実際この姉妹がどうなったかと言うと
As for what happened to the sisters...
姉の方が精神病院に入院したんですよ
The older sister was hospitalized in a psychiatric ward.
妹も精神病院に入院
The younger sister was also hospitalized.
二人とも入院してるんですよ
They're both hospitalized.
はあとさんは呪いたい相手とかいないんですか？
Do you have anyone you want to curse, Haato-san?
私が呪いたい相手…？ いないですね
Someone I want to curse...? No one.
呪っちゃったら自分にも呪った分だけの対価を払わなきゃいけないから
If I curse someone, I'll have to pay the price myself.
そこまでしてやる必要はないかな
I don't think it's worth going that far.
返ってくるんだったら嫌です
I wouldn't want it to come back to me.
クイックに呪えるやつはありますよ
I have something for a quick curse.
呪い教えてくれるんだw
He's teaching me how to curse! lol
呪ったりするんですか？ 田中さん
Do you curse people, Tanaka-san?
僕 呪ったりしますから
I do curse people.
誰呪うんですか？w
Who do you curse? lol
アンチをずっと呪ってます
I'm always cursing my haters (antis).
これは西アフリカの呪術師が作ってくれた
This was made by a sorcerer in West Africa.
どういう効果があるかって言ったら
As for what it does...
刺せるようになっている
You can pierce it.
ここに呪いたい相手の名前を言う
You say the name of the person you want to curse.
名前だけで良いんだ デスノートみたいな
Just the name? Like a Death Note.
おてがる〜 / それで刺すと
How convenient! / Then you pierce it.
そいつに不幸が訪れる
Misfortune will befall them.
一番呪力が強い呪物ってあるんですか？
Is there a cursed object with the strongest curse power?
こんだけ集めてると なんか増えててわからない場合がある
With this many, sometimes they increase and I don't notice.
これどこからもらった…？ 誰からもらったのか
Recently... where did I get this? From whom...?
まったくわからへん 身に覚えがないぞっていう人形がある
I have a doll I don't remember getting.
え、見たいです ぜひお願いします
Oh, I want to see it! Please.
すごい気持ち悪い人形なんですよ
It's a really creepy doll.
ｗｗｗｗｗ
(Laughing)
あれ、タランちゃま…？w
Wait, is that Taran-chama...?
どういう人が作ったんですかね…
I wonder what kind of person made this...
これ私のお姉ちゃんが作ったやつでしょこれ
My older sister made this, you see.
はあとさんのお姉ちゃんが作ったんですか…
Your sister made it...?
私のお姉ちゃんが作った あのクモのね…
My sister made this spider-like thing...
あ、これがね…
Ah, this one...
そうそうそう、これ体もクモになってるんですよ
Yeah, yeah, yeah, its body is also a spider.
けっこうセンスありますよね
She's quite talented.
すごいですよね、これ
It's amazing, isn't it?
ぜひ置いておいてください
Please, feel free to leave it here.
あ、いいんですか？
Oh, is that okay?
じゃあ置いておこうかな…
Well, I'll leave it then...
呪いはない気もするけど
I don't think it's cursed, but...
すごい馴染んでるｗ
It blends in perfectly lol
やっぱりなんもない人形もこういう場所に置いておけば…
Even a doll with no history, if you leave it here...
え、大丈夫ですか？私のお姉ちゃんが作ったんですけど…
Wait, is it okay? My sister made it, but...
お姉ちゃん呪われちゃったりとかしません？
she won't get cursed or anything, right?
お姉ちゃん作ってるだけなんで あ、そっか。作った人か。
She just made it... Ah, I see. She's the creator.
わ、私…？ でもね、はい、
Me...? But you know, yes,
これホンマに…ちょっと…
this is really... a bit...
嫌なこと言いますけど
I'm going to say something unsettling.
えっ、なんですか？
Eh, what is it?
あの…さっきからはあとさんの後ろにずっと誰か居ますよね？
Um... there's been someone behind you the whole time.
あんまし言いたくなかったんですけど
I didn't really want to say it...
ずっと誰か付いてきてますよ
Someone's been following you this whole time.
えっ
What?
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた 愚かな女 またかかった
I called a halt, thought a bit, foolish woman, caught again
だからどうした 自ら望んだと 言ってんじゃん
So what? I told you I wanted this
待ったをかけた ちょっと考えた 少々ちょっと考えた
I called a halt, thought a bit, thought just a little more
だから だからどうした お望み通りの 末路です
So, so what? It's the end you wished for
なんで なんでなんでなんで なんでなんでなの どーゆーつもり
Why, why why why, why is it, what are you intending?
なんで なんでなんでなんで なんでなん ああ そんなもんか
Why, why why why, why... ah, is that all?
ド下層
Bottom tier
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, I guess that's how it is, surely, no doubt
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 絶対に
Well, I guess that's how it is, surely, absolutely
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いない
Well, I guess that's how it is, surely, no doubt
まあそういうもんか そういうもんだ きっとそうだ 違いないの
Well, I guess that's how it is, surely, no doubt about it
違いないよ 絶対
No doubt, absolutely
待ったをかけた ちょっと躊躇った 確かに躊躇った
I called a halt, hesitated a bit, I certainly hesitated
なんだかなぁ なんだかなぁ こういうことではない
Somehow, somehow, it's not like this
待ったをかけた ちょっと躊躇った なんだなんだなんだ あなた
I called a halt, hesitated a bit, what are you?
だから だからこんなことは 望んでないから
So, so I didn't wish for something like this
なんで なんでなんでなんで なんでなんでなの どーゆーつもり
Why, why why why, why is it, what are you intending?
なんで なんでなんでなんで なんで 黙って私に従って
Why, why why why, why... Shut up and obey me
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え 君に一切の拒否権ないよ
Obey, obey, obey, you have no right of refusal
黙って従って 黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey, shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え お願いお願いお願いお願いよ
Obey, obey, obey, please, please, please, please
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え 従え 従えって言ってんの
Obey, obey, obey, obey, I'm telling you to obey
黙って私に従って 黙って私に従って
Shut up and obey me, shut up and obey me
従え 従え 従え お願いお願いお願いお願い...
Obey, obey, obey, please, please, please, please...
お願い
Please
ということで、サロメちゃんに来てもらったよー！
And so, Salome-chan has joined us!
壱、十、百、千、満天サロメ！皆様方を100万点の笑顔にさせますわ！
One, ten, hundred, thousand, Manten Salome! I'll give everyone a 100-point smile!
今はまだ一般人、いつかお嬢様になりたい、そして今日は、はあと様をお祝いに来ましたわ！
I'm still a commoner, but one day I'll be a lady! Today, I'm here to celebrate Haato-sama!
100万点原サロメでございますわ！はあと様〜！
I'm Hyakumantenbara Salome! Haato-sama~!
サロメちゃ〜ん！
Salome-chan~!
来てくれてありがとー！「下層」一緒に歌えてすごく嬉しい！
Thanks for coming! I'm so happy to sing 'Kasou' with you!
歌ってみたも本当に最高でしたわ！
The cover version was also truly amazing!
普段お上品なサロメちゃんのヤンデレ感がたまりませんでした！
I couldn't get enough of the elegant Salome-chan's yandere vibes!
歌い声もお喋り仕方も性格も、好きです！
I love your singing, your way of talking, and your personality!
はあと様、本当にありがとうございますわ！
Haato-sama, thank you so much!
こちらこそ！
Likewise!
なんかこうやって縁が繋がって、今一緒にお歌歌えたのがすごく嬉しいですわ！
I'm so glad our paths crossed and we could sing together like this!
もうすごい、わたくしもはあと様のことも全部可愛いと思ってるし、本当に…
It's wonderful, I think everything about Haato-sama is so cute, truly...
可愛い！
Cute!
おめでとう、今日は本当にありがとうございました、はあと様！
Congratulations, and thank you so much for today, Haato-sama!
こちらこそありがとー！
Thank you too!
さよなら〜！またねー！
Goodbye! See you later!
ようこそお越しなさったご主人様
Welcome home, master
隣に座ってせーの 萌萌萌萌
Come sit with me, and moe moe moe moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who is this even for?
ねぇ教えて 笑顔で up...
Hey, tell me, with a smile, up...
ねぇ教えて 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Hey, tell me, with a smile, up, pull, pull
愛想を忘れてご苦労様
Forget the pleasantries, good work!
私とあなたでせーの
You and I, and here we go!
Luv, luv, luv, luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be happy with this kind of thing?
ねぇ教えて 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Hey, tell me, with a smile, up, pull, pull
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering about, a girl
ふわり ふわり 言葉の層
Lightly drifting, layers of words
それってつまり 幼めな子
That is to say, a childish girl
感情的リアル 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Emotional reality, with a smile, up, pull, pull
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't what they seem
嘘は嘘だと見抜けない
You can't tell a lie is a lie
仕方がないそう その皮
It can't be helped, that skin...
鳥肌サメ肌 アンダートー
...goosebumps, shark skin, undertow
間違ったご指名を頂きます
I'll take the wrong nomination
私とあなたでせーの
You and I, and here we go!
Luv, luv, luv, luv
これはド派手にご苦労様
This is flashily good work
遊びましょう 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Let's play, with a smile, up, pull, pull
ひらり はらり ここはどこ
Fluttering about, where is this?
ふわり ふわり 底冷えショー
Lightly drifting, bone-chilling show
それってつまり 幼めな子
That is to say, a childish girl
感情的リアル 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Emotional reality, with a smile, up, pull, pull
歌い出す 秘密の鐘
The secret bell begins to ring
終わることのないこの世界
In this never-ending world
哀しい子供は
Sad children...
虚しい子供は
...empty children...
眠らせて
...lull them to sleep
おままごと 遊びましょう 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Playing house, let's play, with a smile, up, pull, pull
ひらり はらり 女の子
Fluttering about, a girl
ふわり ふわり 言葉の層
Lightly drifting, layers of words
それってつまり 幼めな子
That is to say, a childish girl
感情的リアル 笑顔で up, pull, pull
Emotional reality, with a smile, up, pull, pull
アップルプル
Up, pull, pull
はあちゃまー！
Haachama!
わあああー！
Waaaa!
誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
来てくれてありがとうー！
Thank you for coming!
なんとね、2021年の、4年ぶりに来ました！
And you know, it's been 4 years since 2021!
4年ぶり！
4 years!
チューリングラブ歌ったの覚えてる？
Do you remember singing Churing Love?
覚えてる！4年前に！
I remember! 4 years ago!
そう、誕生日おめでとう！あの時は若かったね。
Yes, happy birthday! We were young back then.
えっ、今はなんか違う？
Eh, are we different now?
若かったけど、今はクールになったんでね。
We were young, but now we've become cool.
我々今日、クール可愛いかったもんね。
We were cool and cute today, right?
いつものチューリングラブこんなことしたよね。
We did things like this in Churing Love.
オタ芸とかしたからね。
We did wotagei and stuff.
こんなことしてたのに、だいぶクールになりましたよ。
Even though we did that, we've become quite cool.
自由すぎるだろ！
You're being way too free!
今日歌ったモエチャッカファイアで、歌ってみたも出してるので、ぜひ見てください。
We've released a cover of Moechakka Fire that we sang today, so please check it out.
えっ、なんでこの曲にしてくれたんですか？
Eh, why did you choose this song?
えー、これ歌いたかった！
Ah, I wanted to sing this!
やっぱ歌ってみたも出したし、生誕でも一緒に歌いたいなと思って選びました。
I put out a cover, and I wanted to sing it together for my birthday too, so I chose it.
おー、なんか意外な選曲だった、個人的には。
Oh, it was an unexpected choice, personally.
え、なんか今回ホラーライブがテーマなんだけど。
Well, the theme this time is 'Horror Live'.
そんなコンセプトのライブ見たことない！
I've never seen a live with such a concept!
で、なんかちょっと合うかなと思って。
So I thought it might fit a bit.
あー、なるほどね。ちょっとおどろおどろしてね。
Ah, I see. A bit eerie.
なんか一緒に写真とか撮る？
Shall we take some photos together?
撮る！撮る！てかすごいマジで。ライブステージ。
Let's! Let's! But seriously, this live stage is amazing.
えー、なんかいいポーズ。やりたいポーズとかある？
Eh, any good poses? Anything you want to do?
まず普通に、イェーイ！
First normally, yay!
いい感じ！いい感じ！
Looking good! Looking good!
これこれこれこれ。
This, this, this, this.
うわあああー！
Uwaaa!
あれは4年前にもさ、撮ったさ。なんかちょっと座ってエモめな…みたいな。
We took that 4 years ago too. Like sitting down and being emotional...
こっちじゃない？こっちだね。みんなの方向いてね。
Isn't it this way? This way. Facing everyone.
あー、いい！いいじゃん！
Ah, nice! Looks good!
4年前もこれで撮ったんだよ。
We took it like this 4 years ago too.
イェーイ！みんな見てるー？
Yay! Is everyone watching?
久しぶりの星様。
It's been a while, Hosshi-sama.
本当だね、二人とも衣装変わった。
It's true, we both changed costumes.
え、めっちゃ可愛い、その衣装。
Eh, that costume is so cute.
星様もめっちゃ可愛い。あ、これはテーマ間違いなく、足フェチに向けた衣装だね。
Suisei-sama is also very cute. Ah, this is definitely a costume aimed at leg fetishes.
いや、そっちでしょ！
No, that's you!
これは結構隠してるけど
This covers quite a lot, but...
この足よ
Look at these legs!
違う、隠してるのが逆にいいんだって
No, the fact that they're hidden is what makes it good!
あそこからちら見えのね
The peek from there, right?
分かってんね、このあれだもんね
You get it, don't you? It's that thing.
えぐい！絵面がえぐい！
Insane! This shot is insane!
だいぶな絵面じゃなかった今
Wasn't that quite a shot just now?
絶対領域がね
The absolute territory, you know.
どう？なんかセクシーポーズとかしなくて大丈夫？
How about it? Is it okay if I don't do a sexy pose?
セクシーポーズ？したいの？
A sexy pose? You want to?
大丈夫かな？ いや、大丈夫です
Is it okay? No, I'm good.
おめでとう誕生日
Happy Birthday!
はい、ありがとー！
Yes, thank you!
またなんか一緒に歌って踊りたい
I want to sing and dance together again.
うん、踊ろう！是非
Yeah, let's dance! Definitely.
是非ともまた次も踊りましょー
Let's definitely dance together next time too.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
じゃあ、バイバイ！
Well then, bye bye!
あ、バイバイ！頑張ってね！
Ah, bye bye! Good luck!
ありがとー！バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye bye!
正しくなれない 霧が毒をみた
Can't be right, the fog has seen poison
片っ端から確かめたくて
Wanting to check every single thing
考え続けたい
I want to keep thinking
偽りで出会えた
We met through a lie
僕らは何一つも
Since not a single thing of ours
奪われてないから
Has been taken away
僕ら育ってゆくみたい
It seems we're growing up
愛されるみたい
It seems we're being loved
あたたかな波をよむ
Reading the warm waves
可愛い今を選ぶ
Choosing the lovely 'now'
澄んだ朝色
The clear morning color
訪ねる voice で何度でも
With a visiting voice, over and over
僕ら嘘つきだね
We're liars, aren't we?
両想いだね
Our love is mutual
枯れ果てるまで泣き笑い
Laughing and crying until we wither away
今日を受け入れていく
Accepting today
喜びあった日々を忘れはしないけど
I won't forget the days we rejoiced together, but...
知らないほうが幸せだって
They say ignorance is bliss
知れば知り得るほど
But the more I know, the more I can know
正しくなれない 霧がどこをみた
Can't be right, where has the fog seen?
片っ端から確かめたくて
Wanting to check every single thing
考え続けたい
I want to keep thinking
偽りで出会えた
We met through a lie
僕らは何一つも
Since not a single thing of ours
奪われてないから
Has been taken away
今心閉ざさないように
So as not to close my heart now
虎視眈々と暮れを続けよう
Let's keep vigil for the twilight
枯れ木に笑顔だけ
Only a smile on the withered tree
君の肉体欲しい全て
I want your body, everything
無駄に流させないよ
I won't let it go to waste
ねぇ知り得るほど幸せだって
Hey, they say it's happier the more you know
辿り着いてもいい
It's okay to reach the end
君だけが見る夕焼け鏡
The sunset mirror that only you can see
僕でもいつかわかる日まで
Until the day even I can understand
考え続けたい 偽りで出会えた
I want to keep thinking, we met through a lie
シナリオ選ばれるよ
A scenario is chosen
導かれ
Guided
大したもんじゃない 無駄なもんじゃない
It's not a big deal, it's not a waste
しわ寄せを寛大にしていくように
As if to be generous with the consequences
ずっともっとずっと
Forever, more, forever
茶化されようが折れない素直な
Honest, not breaking even if teased
可能性が
The possibility...
見逃せるならば
...if I can overlook it
可能性を
Because I can't give up...
諦められないから
...on the possibility
まだ
Still
正しくなれない 霧がどこをみた
Can't be right, where has the fog seen?
片っ端から確かめたくて
Wanting to check every single thing
考え続けたい
I want to keep thinking
偽りで出会えた
We met through a lie
僕らは何一つも
Since not a single thing of ours
全て嫌われても
Even if everything is hated
奪われてないから
Has been taken away
はあとちゃん、大好きだよ
Haato-chan, I love you.
はあちゃま...
Haachama...
私も大好き
I love you too.
今までごめん
I'm sorry for everything until now.
ごめんなさい
I'm so sorry.
いなくなって
Since you were gone...
寂しかったよ
...I was so lonely.
いつもそばにいるって言ったじゃん
You said you'd always be by my side.
ずっと...
Forever...
待ってたよ
...I've been waiting.
はあ、ちゃま！
Haa, chama!
ちゃま！はあちゃまっちゃま！はあちゃまだよ！
Chama! Haachama-chama! It's Haachama!
こうやって対話するのは初めてだよね。
This is the first time we've conversed like this.
さっき歌ってた『感触』最高だったよ！
The 'Feeling' you sang earlier was awesome!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんか大人っぽくなったね。
You've become quite mature.
実は最近旅をすることが増えまして、
Actually, I've been traveling more lately,
そこで新しい自分を見つけて、ちょっぴり大人っぽい曲にチャレンジしてみました。
and after finding a new side of myself, I tried challenging a slightly more mature song.
ほう！特に好きな歌詞とかはある？
Oh! Are there any lyrics you especially like?
はい。「もう一度もう一度と何度思ったでしょう」という歌詞がありまして、
Yes. There are lyrics that go, 'How many times have I thought, one more time, one more time...'
出会った景色や人の温もりを思いながら、すごく感情移入しました。
thinking about the sights I've seen and the warmth of people, I really put my emotions into it.
おお、そうなんだ！
Oh, I see!
今日リリース予定なので、みんなもたくさん聴いてね！
It's scheduled for release today, so everyone, please listen to it a lot!
そしてそして！デュエットで『正しくなれない』歌ったよ！どうだった？
And, and! We sang 'Can't Be Right' as a duet! How was it?
今までの記憶とか葛藤を振り返りながらでね、すごく心に沁みましたね。
Looking back on past memories and struggles, it really resonated deep in my heart.
本当だよ！
Exactly!
はあとちゃんはさ、ずっと塞ぎ込んで、全然はあちゃまのこと見向きもしないんだもん！
I mean, Haato-chan was always moping and wouldn't even look Haachama's way!
そんなことないけど…ごめんね。
That's not true, but... I'm sorry.
でもお互い知って、分かり合えたからよかったなって思うよ。
But I'm glad we could get to know and understand each other.
おお！ならいっか！
Oh! Then it's fine!
そんな二人の家族写真を、今回は撮ってもらいました！
We had a family photo of the two of us taken this time!
イェーイ！二人の仲良しの証！
Yay! A testament to how close we are!
はい。B2タペストリーになっております！
Yes. It's been made into a B2 tapestry!
おしゃれ！
So stylish!
はあちゃま行くよ！あ、うん！せーの！
Haachama's going! Ah, yeah! One, two!
グッズ！グッズ！ゲットしてください！
Goods! Goods! Please get the goods!
ねえ見て お気に入りの、
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの、お人形さん
one and only doll in the world.
顔も性格も、違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different, but
ずっとみんな、なかよし。
we've always been good friends.
「苦しい」を教わったとき、
When I was taught what "pain" is,
私にもできた 恩返し
I was also able to return the favor.
大事な人、好きな人
Important person, person I like,
いつもそばにいて ほしい、よね。
I always want you by my side, right?
上手に縫ってね、
Sew me up skillfully,
私にしてくれたように。
just like you did for me.
少しほつれたとこも、
Even the parts that are a little frayed
めちゃ 可愛いね。
are so cute.
体をたくさん、
Connecting my body
好きに繋ぎ合わせて。
as you like.
少しいびつだけども、
Even if it's a little misshapen,
大切な 家族たちなの。
they are my precious family.
ねえ見て お気に入りの、
Hey, look at my favorite,
世界に一つの、お人形さん
one and only doll in the world.
顔も性格も、違ったけど
Our faces and personalities were different, but
ずっとみんな、なかよし。
we've always been good friends.
なかよし
Good friends
やさしい。
Gentle.
うれしい。
Happy.
たのしい。
Fun.
いとしい。
Dear.
ほめて。
Praise me.
なでて。
Pet me.
ねえ。
Hey.
上手に縫ってね。
Sew me up skillfully.
私にしてくれたように、
Just like you did for me,
少しほつれたとこも、
even the parts that are a little frayed
めちゃ 可愛いね。
are so cute.
体をたくさん、
Connecting my body
好きに繋ぎ合わせて。
as you like.
少しいびつだけども、
Even if it's a little misshapen,
大切な。
Precious.
たいせつな、
Precious,
だ”い”ぜ”つ”な、
precious,
大切な
precious
家族たちなの。
family.
かぞくたちなの
We're family.
生誕ライブ限定
Limited-edition birthday live...
グッズ販売のお知らせ！
...merch announcement!
家族写真B2タペストリー。
Family Photo B2 Tapestry.
ゴージャスな額縁風デザインと肖像画のような二人がとってもキュート。
A gorgeous frame-like design and a cute portrait of us.
お部屋の壁に、今日の思い出を飾って
Decorate your wall with today's memories,
彩り豊かな推し活ができちゃいます。
for a colorful fan life.
おでかけちゃまぬいぐるみ、タランちゃドレス衣装ver。
Outing-Chama Plushie (Tarancha Dress Outfit Ver.).
ボタン風の目がとっても可愛いぬいぐるみ。
A plushie with very cute button-like eyes.
丁寧にひとつひとつ再現された
Meticulously recreated one by one,
ドレス衣装のちゃまと一緒におでかけして旅に出れちゃいます！
you can go on a trip with Chama in her dress!
鞄に付けれるハートチャーム付き。
Comes with a heart charm to attach to your bag.
タランちゃまぬいぐるみポーチ。
Tarancha Plushie Pouch.
あのタランちゃまがポーチに！？
That Taranchama is now a pouch!?
背中のファスナーが開いて収納できる便利アイテム。
A handy item with a zipper on the back for storage.
ゴスロリ衣装のタランちゃまが可愛すぎる！
Taranchama in a gothic lolita outfit is just too cute!
チェーンがついてるから安心して、お外にお散歩させられるよ。
With the chain, you can safely take her for a walk outside.
タランちゃまスマホリング。
Taranchama Smartphone Ring.
スマホの落下はタランちゃまにお任せ！
Leave preventing phone drops to Taranchama!
しっかり張り付いて守ってくれます。
She'll stick on tight and protect it.
愛くるしいお目目とつい目が合っちゃう瞬間も
Those moments when you lock eyes with her adorable face...
癒されてたまりません！
...it's so incredibly soothing!
全部セットは数量限定もあります。
The full set is also available in limited quantities.
フルセット購入特典の数量限定バージョンは、
The limited edition full set bonus includes
箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードと、
a foil-stamped postcard with a message,
赤井はあと直筆サイン、
a handwritten signature by Akai Haato,
特典ボイス『ひみつのはなし』もあるよ！
and a bonus voice track, 'A Secret Tale'!
PRカードもあるよ！
There's also a PR card!
hololive公式ECサイトで販売中！
Now on sale at the hololive official EC site!